Dr.Tal Ben-Shahar:Any announcement today? Anyone? No.
今天有人有消息宣布吗 没有
OK.Good morning.
好的 早上好
What we are going to do today is finish up on perfectionism
我们今天要把完美主义讲完
and then move on to the mind body.
然后开始讲精神肉体
This semester for me has been going great.
这个学期对我来说挺不错的
There are very few things that
没有什么东西
I regret about not having done this semester,
让我后悔做过
but there is one thing that I will change next time
不过下次我还想挑战点别的
when I teach the class,that I already know of now,
教这门课时 我现在知道了
is have the lecture on the mind body earlier.
应该更早讲精神肉体的
Because it is such an important topic.
因为这个话题十分重要
It is so foundational,so basic that when I realized that-
它是如此根本而且基础 因此当我意识到
and that was earlier on this semester that
在这个学期很早的时候就意识到
I should have had it earlier,
我应该早点讲
I started already to plug for physical exercise,
我那时就开始停止介绍身体锻炼
to talk about mindfulness,
开始讲"念"的概念
to introduce it a little bit on a lower level of the spiral.
从较低一点的层次来介绍它
So today,you know,a month or two- too late perhaps,
今天 在一两个月之后
we are going to introduce the mind body connection,
我们要再讲讲精神和肉体的联系
physical health.
身体的健康
But first,let me introduce- let me finish up on perfectionism.
首先我们先把完美主义讲完
So remember last time we talked about the two models-
上节课我们讲到了两个模型
the schema of the perfectionist,
完美主义的基模
a straight line from point A to point B
一条从A到B的直线
versus the schema of the person committed to excellence
以及追求卓越的基模
which is much more meandering spiral kind-of journey.And
更像是蜿蜒曲折的螺旋上升
a couple of people yesterday in office hours asked the question,
有些人昨天在办公时间来问我
"so what is really the difference?"
"区别到底在哪里"
So you gave us the model of rat racer-
我们可以用无意义追逐目标的人来类比
you know that person- remember- who at the age of 72,
还记得那个72岁的人吗
gets to being,quite literally on top of the world,
他达到了很高的地位
overlooking central park
管理着世界的中心
and then being informed after a life of constant stress,
在承受了一生的压力
constantly living the future in point B,
不停地追逐到达B点
not enjoying the present,the journey,
而不是享受当下 享受旅途之后被告知
is being told it is time to retire.
退休的时候到了
And I asked you a simple question,
我问你们一个简单的问题
"what kind of life do you want for yourself?"
"你想要怎样的生活"
So what is the alternative model? What is the positive model?
那么另一种模型是怎样的呢 积极的模型是怎样的
Now the positive model from the outside may look exactly the same
积极的模型从外表上看来似乎一模一样
It may be a person who is extremely ambitious,
可能也是一个充满雄心壮志的人
a person who is extremely hard working,
极度勤奋刻苦的人
a person who is an investment banker or a doctor,
可能是个投资银行家 或者是个医生
or a lawyer,or a teacher,or working at a homeless shelter.
或者律师 老师 或者在流浪者之家工作
It may look the exactly same from the outside.
从外表上看可能完全一样
From the inside,it is radically different.
但其内在则是迥然相异
How is it radically different?
怎么个迥然相异法呢
In that the person who is on the excellence side,
区别在于这个追求卓越的人
may be as ambitious,may have the same goals,
也许同样充满雄心壮志 有同样的目标
may reach the same goals.
也可能达到了同样的目标
However,that person also enjoys the journey.
然而这个人同时享受这个旅程
That is the difference.
这就是区别所在
So yes,he or she gets into a top school,
是的 他或她会进入名校
a school that they really wanted to get into.
进入他们非常想进的学校
And at school they work extremely hard.
在学校里他们非常勤奋刻苦
However,they also learn it that they are able to,mostly-
但同时他们也知道 他们几乎可以
there's no 100 percent here- but mostly,
不是完全 但几乎可以
enjoy their time in school,with the same ups and downs,
享受他们在学校的所有时光 同样的起伏坎坷
the vicissitudes- natural- but enjoy school
同样的兴衰变迁 但他们享受这个过程
and then get into the job they really wanted
然后获得他们想要的工作
or one of the job they wanted,and work extremely hard there,
或者他们想要的工作之一 然后继续努力工作
and be ambitious,and work the 80 hour weeks.
充满雄心壮志 每周工作80个小时
However,that person also overall enjoys the journey.
然而这个人同样享受整个过程
And then they enjoy the next step and being associate,
然后他们享受下一个旅途 和别人合作
being a partner,and being the MD or whatever it is.
成为别人的搭档 当上营销总监之类的
The only difference is that they enjoy the journey.
唯一的区别就在于他们享受这个过程
Now I have a few role models that I know.
我还可以举出一些实例
One of them is my ex-roommate,who is an investment banker.
其中之一就是我的前室友 他是个投资银行家
We were in college together,also class of 96.
我们一起上大学 也是96届的
After graduating,being an economist major,
毕业之后 由于其经济学的专业
worked for one of the premier hedge funds.
给一个著名的对冲基金工作
After that,came back to Harvard,got his JD MBA.
之后他就回到哈佛 获得法律博士和工商管理硕士的双学位
Did extremely well here as a JD MBA.
学业非常优秀
Had all the offers that he wanted after.
之后就获得了所有他想要的机会
Chose another hedge fund.
他又选择了另一家对冲基金
And went off on his own and started a firm with a few friends.
之后他又自立门户 和一些朋友一起开了一家公司
Now when I talked to him about investment banking
当我和他谈起投资银行时
which I know very little about,
我对此了解很少
I get very excited about investment banking.
我对投资银行表现得很兴奋
Because his excitement is contagious.
因为他的兴奋能感染我
He looks forward to work every day.
他每天都期待着工作
And he works long hours.
他工作的时间也很长
So he is a model of a person committed to excellence.
他就是一个追求卓越的例子
Even though from the outside,
虽然从表面上看
it may look the exact same as the "caricature"
就和我之前描述的形象
that I depicted earlier.
一模一样
So it's not about losing our ambition.
因此不是要我们失去雄心壮志
It's not about not being competitive.
也不是变得没有竞争力
If that is what makes you happy.
如果那能让你快乐的话
It is simply learning to also enjoy the process,
这只是让你们学会享受过程
the step on the way to a destination
朝着你认为有意义的目的地
that you deem valuable that is important to you.
所迈出的步子才是最重要的
Now the question is,"how do we overcome this perfectionism,
而问题在于 "我们如何克服完美主义
this constant knot in our stomach?
这个解不开的结呢"
How do we overcome this living in the future,
我们如何克服活在未来中的感觉
being afraid of the present because what if I fail?
因为害怕失败而害怕当下的感觉
And I started to describe a few methods:
我讲了一些方法
the first one is being aware of it-
首先是认识它
being aware of what I want to change
认识到我想改变什么
and what I want to maintain.
我想保持什么
Remember Ellen Langer's study-
还记得Ellen Langer的研究吗
about getting a more nuance understanding
关于更确切地了解
of what it is that I want to change.
我到底想改变什么
Because for very long time,
因为长久以来
I couldn't,couldn't become less of a perfectionist
我都是个完美主义者
because associated with perfectionism,with also success,
因为总是想着完美 总是想着成功
my subconscious were stopping me from letting go of perfectionism
我的潜意识让我没法摆脱完美主义
because I thought that also means
因为我会认为那就意味着
throwing out baby with bath water,i.e.my success.
把宝宝和洗澡水一起冲走了 也就是成功被冲走了
But now that I have a more nuance understanding of perfectionism
但现在我更确切地了解了完美主义
which is an incapacitating fear of failure,
它就是一种对失败的无法抑制的恐惧
and I understand that I can still be as ambitious
我明白了我仍然可以充满抱负
and not give up my success,
而无需放弃成功
and yet enjoy the process- that's a better understanding.
同时享受这个过程 这是更好的理解
And now I can move forward.
这样我就能继续前进
So the first step is awareness.
因此第一步就是认识
After we have awareness,
在我们获得了认识之后
it's about going back to Dweck's notion of rewarding effort.
就是Dweck关于工作回报的概念
Remember,Carol Dweck was able to change students
记住Carol Dweck能够在短短几小时内
and adult's mind set with as little as a few hours.
就改变学生和成人的思维模式
And sometimes,
有时候
this mind set has been set in them from a very young age.
这些思维模式在他们非常小的时候就已经奠定了
The fixed versus the malleable mind set.
思维模式是固定的 还是可塑的
And Carol Dweck by teaching them the malleability,
Carol Dweck通过教他们可塑性
the neuroplasticity- how our brain constantly changes
神经的可塑性 我们的大脑是时刻在变化的
by teaching them that to focus on the journey,on the effort,
通过教他们关注过程 关注所付出的努力
as opposed to the outcomes,as opposed to the intelligence,
而不是结果 或者最后的成就
was able to change their mind set.
从而改变他们的思维模式
So in ourselves we can focus on a reward on our effort,
我们自己也可以关注我们付出的努力
on our process,whether it's failure or success.
关注过程本身 不管它是失败还是成功
Active acceptance.
主动地去接受
It will always be part of us.
它将永远是我们的一部分
You know one of the things that perfectionist very often do
完美主义者经常会做的一件事
when they realize they are perfectionists,
当他们意识到自己是完美主义者时
and that is hurting them:
这让他们很难受
they apply the perfectionist approach to overcoming perfectionism
他们就用完美主义的方式来克服完美主义
which means,
也就是说
I will become perfect person who is committed to excellence.
我会成为一个完美的追求卓越的人
That doesn't work.That's just more perfectionism.
这不会起作用的 只是更进一步的完美主义
But what active acceptance is about saying,
但主动的接受意味着
"OK.So I'm not...So I'm still a perfectionist.
"好吧 我仍旧是个完美主义者
I will always probably have part of it in me.
我可能永远都会有这方面的性格
And that's OK.And that's OK."
这没关系 没有关系"
One of the things that Buddhists talk about is that very often,
佛教徒会说的一句话是 通常情况下
our greatest challenges,
我们面临的最大挑战
what Karen Horney would call "our neurosis"-
Karen Horney会称之为"神经官能症"
whether it's perfectionism,the fear of failure,
不管是完美主义 对失败的恐惧
whether it's anger that comes up once in a while,anxiety,
还是时不时出现的愤怒 焦虑
whatever it is that we have- that "issue".
不管我们的问题是什么
The Buddhists cognitively reframe it and say,
佛教徒很巧妙地重新定义了它
"we need to look at it as a tool,as a tool for growth,
"我们要将其视为一种工具 一种成长的工具
as a way of learning about ourselves,
一种了解自己的方式
digging deep inside ourselves and growing."
使我们深入挖掘自己 然后得以成长"
So to look at it- OK,so this is an opportunity for growth,
要这样看它 这是个成长的机会
for personal learning,for reflection,
了解自我 反省自身的机会
for more empathy toward other people- whatever it is.
能够更设身处地为别人着想的机会 无论它是什么
But to look at it as a tool.
将其视为一种工具
Accept it.And then act.
接受它 然后行动
Can one of the TFs- do you mind seeing what it is,please?
有助教能查查看它到底怎么了吗
Thanks,John.
谢谢 John
The next thing,after we accept it,we go ahead and change it.
下一步 在接受它之后 我们就去改变它
And we go ahead and change it by introducing behavior.
我们要通过建立行为来改变它
The key issue here is behavior.
这里的关键在于行为
Now one of the things that I did as I told you last time
我上节课讲过的一件我做过的事
was started to solicit feedback from people,
就是向别人寻求反馈
started to solicit criticism.
寻求批评
Initially,literally I need to catch myself from responding,
一开始我要控制自己不去回答
from attacking back.
不去顶嘴反驳
Why? Because criticism is the deviation from a straight narrow,
为什么 因为批评是对直线箭头的偏离
from that schema.
偏离那个基模
But over time I got used to it.It actually helped me.
但我逐渐习惯了 这真的帮到了我
And now I'm much open to criticism.
我现在更能够包容批评
Still,
然而
sometimes catch myself when I want to respond and attack back.
我有时仍会想回答 想顶嘴反驳
But overall,I got better through behavior changing attitude.
但总体来说 我通过改变态度的行为变得更好
Something else- putting myself on the line more,
还有一点 使自己更经常处于水平线上
whether it's the story that I told you about Brittany,
包括我跟你们讲的关于Brittany的故事
who said no a few consecutive times.
连续说了几次不
And that's OK.So she said no.
但没关系 她说不
I'm still here.I survived.
我还在这 我还活着
Learn to fail or fail to learn.
屡战屡败 屡败屡战
Next,we don't always have to act out in the world;
下一步 我们不一定要外在地表现出行为
we can also act in our internal simulator-
我们也可以在内心中模拟
the mind doesn't know the difference
你的思想是无法分辨
between the real thing and the imaginary thing.
现实和想象的区别的
And therefore,I can imagine myself,see myself,
因此我可以想象自己 幻想自己
acting as a person committed to excellence.
就像一个追求卓越的人一样
So for example,before teaching,
比如说在上课之前
one of the things that I visualize
我想象的一件事就是
is seeing myself there on the stage,feeling light,
假想我自己站在台上 感觉很轻松
calm and accepting- in other words,
冷静 并且很包容 换句话说
a way that a person committed to excellence would,as opposed
想象追求卓越的人会用的方式
to a perfectionist would be constantly afraid of failure.
而非总是害怕失败的完美主义者
And the mind doesn't the know the difference
你的大脑是不会知道有什么区别的
and the mind looks for consistency.
你的大脑需要一致性
And therefore,I'm able to be that way
因此我就能那样去做
or much more likely to be that way because of the visualization.
或者更容易那样去做 因为我先幻想了
Also,meditation in and of itself helps.
同时冥想也会有所帮助
We'll talk about meditation- probably get to it on Thursday.
我们可能会在周四讲到冥想
Cause meditation puts us in a state of mind of calm,
因为冥想能使我们处于冷静的状态
of acceptance,a state of being,as opposed to state of doing.
能够接受事物 是一种存在 而非一种行为
And when we are in a state of being,we are here and now,
当我们作为一种存在时 我们就能活在当下
we are enjoying the process,
我们就能享受过程
as opposed to constantly thinking about the destination,
而不是总想着目的地
and what will happen if I don't get to that destination.
以及如果我达不到这个目标会怎么样
But more on that on Thursday.
周四我们会更深入地探讨
This is a technique,method that I learn from Samuel Coleridge,
这是我从Samuel Coleridge那里学来的方法
the British philosopher,
一个英国的哲学家
late 18th century and the beginning of the 19th century,
活跃于18世纪末 19世纪初
one of the philosophers who influence our Ralph Waldo Emerson.
影响了爱默生的哲学家之一
And what Coleridge did- he had an issue with perfectionism
Coleridge本身是个完美主义者
and perfectionism as Winston Churchill later on said
后来丘吉尔说完美主义
"means paralysis"-
"就是瘫痪"
and he experienced this paralysis when he came to writing.
他在写作时就经历了这样的"瘫痪"
Writing was the most important thing in his life.
写作是他生命中最重要的一件事
But he really couldn't write well.
但他就是没法写好
Because he was so afraid of not writing the ultimate essay,
因为他很害怕写不出那终极的文章
or the ultimate poem.
或者终极的诗
So here was what he did: he said,"well,at the end of my life,
所以他所做的是 他说 "在我生命的结尾
I will write my magnum opus.
我会写出我的巨著
Until then,everything is rough draft."
在那之前 一切都只是草稿"
And that liberated him.
这让他得到解放
Because he wasn't worried any more.
因为他不再焦虑了
Now he never got to write his magnum opus.
他再也不用想着写巨著
But at the meantime,he wrote dozens of beautiful poems-
而同时 他写出了无数优美的诗篇
some of them the most beautiful in the English language
有些是英语中最美的文字
and numerous very powerful,
以及许多非常强有力的
influential and beautifully crafted essays.
具有影响的 结构精妙的文章
And they were all "rough drafts".
而他们都只是"草稿"
So there wasn't the pressure.This helped me a lot.
这样就没有压力了 这给了我很大的帮助
Because what I do when I thought about this,I said,"OK.
当我想到这个时 我说 "好吧
So let's see one of the domains-
看看完美主义
where perfectionism was very strong for me
对我影响最深的一个领域吧
because it was an important domain- was teaching."
因为这个领域对我很重要 就是教学"
Then I said to myself,"OK." And this was close to 10 years ago.
我就对自己说 "好吧" 这是大约十年前的事了
I said,"in 20 years,I'm going to have a leadership institute
我说"二十年后 我会在名列前茅的
in which I'm going to be teaching.
学院中任教
Amazing workshops and seminars and lectures.
能开很棒的学术报告和研讨会
Until then,everything is rough draft.
在那之前 一切都只是草稿
Until then,everything is preparation." And that took off...
在那之前 一切都只是准备" 这真的起作用了
Now I know this is a mental game.
我现在知道这是个心理游戏
I mean I know I am "fooling myself".
我知道我是在骗自己
Because in 12 years from now,when that goal is actually,
因为12年后 等目标要到了的时候
when I'm there 20 years later,
20年到了的时候
I'm going to set another goal for 20 years later.
我会再定一个20年后的计划
To liberate me so that I can enjoy the here and now.
来解放我自己 这样我才能享受当下
So that I can enjoy the process,
这样我才能享受过程
as opposed to be stuck on it having to be perfect,
而不是执着于要变得完美
flawless everyday experience,which it can never be.
毫无半点瑕疵 这是永远无法达到的
So end goal can often be liberating.
因此制定一个终极目标可以让你解放
The Platinum Rule.
这是铂金法则
So the Golden Rule:
黄金法则就是
do not do unto others what you would not have done unto yourself"
"己所不欲勿施于人"
Or "do unto others what you would unto yourself."
或者说"己所欲方施于人"
The foundation of most moral systems,most religions today.
这是当今很多道德体系和宗教信仰的基础
The Platinum Rule is taking the Golden Rule
铂金法则就是取自黄金法则
and switching it around.
再对其进行小小的修饰
And what it says is,
它说的是
"do not do unto yourself what you would not do unto others."
"人所不欲勿施于己"
Or rather "do unto yourself what you do unto others."
或者说"人所欲方施于己"
Now if a good friend of you,someone you really care about
如果你的一个好朋友 你非常在乎的一个人
or a family member fails and doesn't do well,
或者家庭成员失败了 没做好
what you'll do with that person? Do you reject that person?
你会怎样对待这个人 你会排斥这个人吗
"Oh you just got a B on this exam."
"你考试只得了个B"
Or "you didn't win this competition."
或者"你竟然没赢得比赛"
Is that how you treat them? Or do you embrace them?
你会这样对待他们吗 还是你会拥抱他们
And do you love them any less for it? Of course not.
你们会因此少爱他们一点吗 当然不会
Then why do we apply these unrealistic
那么为什么我们要将这些不现实的
and non-compassionate standards to ourselves?
毫无共鸣的标准强加给我们自己呢
Now the Dalai Lama,
达赖喇嘛
when he was first introduced to a lot of Western culture,
当他刚开始大量接触西方文化时
was baffled by one very particular thing:
被一样东西困扰了
by our usage of a word,compassion.
就是我们用的一个词 同情
The word compassion in Tibetan is "tsewe",
同情这个词在藏语中叫"tsewe"
in English spelled "t-s-e-w-e".
拼为"t-s-e-w-e"
The word in Tibetan means
这个词在藏语中的意思
compassion for others as well as for self.
既是同情他人 也是同情自己
And he was really taking back by the notion that in English
所以他完全被英语中的概念搞糊涂了
when we talk about,or in West in general- not just in English-
或者说在大多数西方文化 不仅是英语文化中
when we talk about compassion,
当我们说到同情时
we talk about compassion for others.
我们是指对别人的同情
And he said,"how can you have compassion for others
他说"你们对自己没有同情
when you don't have compassion for yourself?"
又怎么能对别人有同情呢"
The foundation is the self.
自我是基础
The Platinum Rule
铂金法则
is about having compassion for ourselves as well.
就是说对我们自己也要有同情
Not treating ourselves differently than we would others.
对待自己不能不同于对待别人
Holding...Having similar standards.
要有同样的标准
Accepting failure in the same way that we accepted in others,
要像接受别人 我们所爱的人的失败一样 去接受
in people we love.
我们自己的失败
After all,why not? How do we help other people?
为什么不呢 我们是如何帮助别人的
Because very often when we are in relationships,
因为通常我们处于一段感情中时
people are in relationships with a perfectionist or,
和完美主义者有感情的人
we know a friend of ours is a perfectionist,
或者我们有个朋友是完美主义者的话
how do we help other people?
我们如何去帮助别人
The first thing that is important to make very clear is that
首先要搞清楚的一件重要的事就是
it is extremely difficult to help other people
帮助别人是非常困难的
deal with perfectionism.
处理完美主义的问题
It mostly has to come from within.
通常都要从内部着手
They have to want a change.
他们必须要渴望改变
Because it takes time.
因为这是需要时间的
Doesn't happen over night.
不是立竿见影的
I know it from research or I know it from personal experience.
我从研究中 或者个人经历中了解到这一点
And yet,we can help,after accepting that it is difficult.
但我们还是能去帮助他人 即使知道这很困难
The first most important thing to do is by example.
首先最重要的事就是树立榜样
If I can change,
如果我能改变
and become more a person committed to excellence,
成为一个追求卓越的人
enjoy the journey,celebrate even failures,
享受过程 即使失败也要庆祝
even falling down once in a while.
即使偶尔挫折也要庆祝
Then I'm leading by example.
那我就做出了榜样
And remember that experiment,right?
还记得那个实验吧
People do what you do,rather than what you say.
人们更愿意照着你所做的去做 而不是你说的话
Second thing to do is to tell stories about it,
第二件事就是分享这个故事
which is what this lecture is essentially,
也就是这门课
the last two lectures were about-
上两节课所讲的内容
mostly,personal stories of how I moved or am moving
基本上是关于我个人如何从
from being a perfectionist to being committed to excellence.
完美主义者变为追求卓越者的故事
So telling stories,sharing.
讲故事 互相分享
Again,the difference between sharing and telling:
再次强调分享和讲的区别
sharing,both of us get; telling is one way street.
分享 两者皆有收获 讲就只是单行道
And finally,another way to,to help other people
最后还有一种帮助别人的方式
is remembering what Carol Dweck was all about.
回忆一下Carol Dweck的研究
Rewarding effort.Rewarding the journey.
工作回报 过程的回报
It is so easy to fall into the track of rewarding outcome,
很容易陷入对结果的回报之中
and so easy to forget to reward the journey.
也很容易忘记回报过程
I know that's difficult in child rearing with my kids.
我在抚养我的小孩时就觉得很困难
And it's certainly difficult in a relationship.
在感情之中也很难做到
It's certainly difficult being the boss or a friend.
作为上司或者朋友当然也很难
But to really focus on rewarding the journey,
但一定要注意回报过程
on pointing out "oh this was a great attempt"
要指出来"这是个不错的尝试"
or "this was so much fun doing it"- the process.
或者"这真是太有趣了" 注重过程
I want to end this lecture
我想通过做一个
by introducing a mini summary of the course so far.
对至今为止所讲内容的小小总结来结束这个话题
This is a technique- quite a simple technique,
这是个技巧 一个很简单的技巧
but a technique that I found very powerful.
但我发现是个很有用的技巧
Because what it does is synthesize a lot of what we discussed
因为它能够整合我们目前为止所见过的
until now in the course.
所有内容
And this specific technique I apply to difficult situations
我将这个技巧应用于各种困境中
when I'm facing periods in my life and it could be a long period
当我在面对人生中很困难的一段时期 可能是很长的一段时期
or one day that is very difficult for me.
也可能是很困难的一天时
You know,when I'm experiencing anxiety or stress,
当我感受到焦虑或压力
or strong levels,or high levels of disappointment.
或者深深的失望时
And this is the alternative in many ways to the three Ms-
这是除了三个M之外的另一种选择
so remember the three Ms? Magnifying.Minimizing.
还记得三个M吗 放大 减小
And Making-up,inventing.
以及编造 发明
So the three Ps are the alternative.
三个P则是另一种选择
The first p is the Permission to be human.
第一个P就是准许自己为人
So if I experience a difficult experience,I have some...
如果我经历了困难
I go through a hard time.
我遇到了挫折
The first step is to give myself permission
第一步就是给自己许可证
and that would mean accepting of the emotion,
也就是说接受这样的感情
accepting that is difficult,accepting reality.
接受这个困境 接受现实
Something just happened;
它已经发生了
there is nothing I can do about what had just happened.
我对此什么也做不了
What can change is perhaps my interpretation of what had happened
能够改变的只有我对它的诠释
which is where I get to the next level.
这时我就会进入下一个层次
The next step.
到下一步
And this is reframing,interpreting the situation as Positive.
也就是重建 将情况诠释为积极的
And that would be the benefit finder.
这就是积极者
What's the silver lining here?
这其中有什么闪光点
What is the growth opportunity here?
其中有什么成长的机会
So if I am going through a very difficult time,
所以如果我经历了困境
perhaps look at it through the Buddhist perspective and say,
也许可以用佛教的眼光来看待
"well,this is a tool for growth;
"这是成长的工具
this will help me better understand myself as well as others,
这可以帮助我更好地了解自己 了解他人
become a better psychologist,become a better business person,
成为一个更好的心理学家 成为一个更好的商人
whatever it is.
诸如此类
Seeing it again,the silver lining,the opportunity in failure.
再次发掘出失败中的闪光点 失败中的机会
And finally,
最后
one very important technique that we didn't talk about much,
我们没怎么提到的一个非常重要的技巧
just in passing,is distracting,distraction;
就粗略提到过的 就是分心
is looking toward other place.
将注意力转向别处
It's not always good.In fact,
这不一定是件好事
we will talk about next time it's sometimes detrimental to stay
我们下节课会讲到 有时执着于
and analyze every single emotion,feeling,thought that comes up.
分析每种情感 感觉和想法 是有害的
Ruminating in and of itself does not always help.
反复思考并不一定有帮助
Sometimes the best thing to do
有时最好的方法
is when a negative thought comes up,
就是当消极的想法
or a negative feeling comes up
或者负面的情绪出现时
is to distract ourselves from it by,for example,
将我们的注意力转到别处去 比如说
going to listen to a piece of music,going for a run,
听听音乐 跑个步
talking to someone either about that or something else.
和别人聊聊这件事或者别的事
Now this is very different from avoiding.
这和逃避是很不一样的
Because it is not about saying,"all right,
因为这并不是说 "好吧
I am not going to deal with any of the issues in my life."
我一辈子不要再管这种事了"
It's just saying that if there is a recurrent thought or feeling,
这只是说如果某种情绪或想法反复出现
and I'm experiencing a Sisyphean battle against it- you know,
我永远都在徒劳地抗争
pushing the stone up and being pushed down again,
把石头推上去 然后又被推下来
up and down again.
上上下下
Sometimes it is better,more helpful to just say,
有时更好 更有用的方法是
"OK,I'm not going to ruminate; it's pointless.
"好吧 我不要再反复想了 这没有意义
This neural pathway in my mind is being so reinforced.
这个神经通路在我脑海中太强烈了
It's not going anywhere." And then to say,"let me move on.
不会有任何出路的" 然后说 "让我继续前进吧
Let me listen to a nice piece of music.
让我去听首好歌
Let me go for a run that will really help get my mind off this."
让我去跑个步 好让我能够真正忘记它"
And very often
很经常地
what a run can do is also help me look at it in a different,
跑步还能使我从全新的角度
through a different lens.
来看待这件事
And we'll talk about it,much more about this distraction,
我们会更深入地探讨这个分心
because it's nuanced,meaning we are not about avoiding.
因为差异非常微小 并不是逃避
So we'll talk about it next,
我们下节课
on Thursday when we talk about dealing with depression
周四讲到处理沮丧
or dealing with anxiety,using meditation,
或者焦虑时 会用到冥想
using mindfulness as a kind of distraction.
用念来分心
But that's also one way of looking at the positive.
但那也是一种积极对待的方式
And finally,the third p is about taking Perspective.
最后 第三个P是指换个角度
Is this really gonna matter?
这真的很重要吗
This is Richard Carlson's wonderful self-help book,
Richard Carlson写了一本很好的自助书
"Don't Sweat the Small Stuff... and it's all Small Stuff".
"别为小事伤神 一切皆是小事"
Now I don't necessarily agree with the second-
我不完全同意后半句
"it's all small stuff",but certainly
"一切皆是小事" 但很显然
a lot of things that we sweat about in our lives are small stuff.
许多生活中我们为之伤神的事都是小事
Now the issue with not sweating the small stuff
要不为小事伤神
is asking a simple question: is this going to matter in a year?
就要问一个简单的问题 它在一年后会不会有影响
Or in a grand...
或者更久...
You know,in a large schema of things,does it really matter?
从长远来看 它真的很重要吗
Is it worth my worrying,and fretting,
它真的值得我去担心 焦虑
and being depressed and upset and anxious about this now?
为之沮丧 为之焦躁吗
Is this really going to matter in a year?
它在一年之后真的会有影响吗
And most of the times,it won't matter.
通常情况下都不会
The other side of this is that well,then does anything matter?
从另一方面说 有什么是真的重要的吗
A few years ago,I was asked a very simple question by a friend.
几年前 有个朋友问了我一个非常简单的问题
And he said,"you know,just..."
他说
You know we haven't talked about before- this was a close friend.
我们之前从来没聊过这个的 他是我很好的朋友
But..."Can you tell me what psychological maturity is?
但也没聊过 "你能告诉我心理成熟是什么吗
From your research,
通过你的研究
can you think about what psychological maturity is?"
你能想明白心理成熟到底是什么吗"
And off-the-cuff,
就在这一霎那
at that moment- over time I revise the definition a little bit-
就在当时 后来我又对这个定义做了些修饰
I said the following: Psychological maturity
我当时这么说 心理成熟
is about the ability to willingly shift perspective.
就是根据自己的意愿转换角度的能力
And I think it's more or less right.Again,
我觉得这差不多是对的
looking at the research about this ability to shift perspective.
基于这些关于转换角度的能力的研究
Why? Or what is this ability to shift perspective?
为什么  这种转换角度的能力是什么
It's the ability when we want to be immersed in the here and now,
这就是我们希望沉浸在当下的
in the present.
一种能力
And it's the ability to,when we want,take a step back,
也正是我们退一步
zoom out both in time and in space,and ask the question,
时间和空间上都退一步 问这样的问题
"is this really going to matter? Or in a year?
"它真的有影响吗 一年之后呢
Or in a grand schema of things,space? Is this really important?"
或者更长远来看呢 它真的很重要吗"
And at the same time,go back almost at will.
同时随心所欲地回来
Have this flexibility to go back
能够灵活地将思绪拉回来
and be immersed when listening to a beautiful piece of music,
沉浸于聆听一首美妙的歌
or spending time with people we love.
或者和我们所爱的人一起
And again,it's easier said than done.
说起来容易 做起来难
But over time,we can train our mind through meditation,
但逐渐我们可以通过冥想来训练我们的思想
through cognitively reframing things.
通过对事物进行认知重建
We can train our mind
我们可以训练我们的思想
to be able to make that shift almost at will.
使其能够按照我们的意愿来转换
So let me give you an example of the three Ps applied.
我来给你们举个应用三个P的例子吧
So this happened to me at the beginning of the semester,
这是刚开学时发生在我身上的事
about two weeks into the semester.
大约开学后两个星期
I was...I had to take Shirell,my daughter to day care.
我要带我的女儿Shirell去托儿所
And I was running late.I was running really late.
我就要迟到了 迟了很多
And you know what I like to do before lectures is to work out.
你们知道我上课前一般都会去健身
Now I realized I was not going to have time to work out,
我意识到我没时间去健身了
I hardly had any time to go over the lecture notes that
我甚至几乎没时间复习备课笔记
I do twice in the morning before the lecture.
我在上课前都会复习两遍
And I got upset.And I became stressed.
于是我很沮丧 很有压力
Then I said,"OK.Let's take the three Ps and apply them."
然后我说 "就用用三个P吧"
First P,permission.Acceptance.
第一个P 许可 接受
I said to myself,"OK.So you are stressed.So you are upset.
我对自己说 "你压力很大 你很沮丧
It's OK to be upset.It's OK to be stressed.
这些都没关系
Even if you do teach positive psychology.It's all right."
即使你是教积极心理学的 也没关系"
The second thing that I said- respect for reality.
我说的第二件事就是尊重现实
This is the beginning of the semester.
这是学期刚开始的时候
A lot of things are happening.
很多事情都碰在一起
We had just arrived from Israel a couple of weeks earlier.
我们几个星期前刚从以色列回来
A little bit of jet lag.The kids.
要倒时差 还有小孩要照顾
Respect for reality.It is what it is.
尊重现实 现实就是这样
And then I moved on to positive.
然后我转向第二个P 积极性
So what's the benefit here? So the first benefit is- well,
有什么好处呢 第一个好处就是
I need to think more about where I can simplify,
我要更仔细地想想我能简化的地方
what I can say no to.
我可以说不的地方
Do less rather than more.So that's certainly a benefit there.
做少一点而非做多一点 这是很显然的一个好处
Because it got me thinking about it.
因为它让我去思考
The second benefit that I thought about at that moment-
第二个好处就是当时我想
"oh now I have another story to tell in class.
"我现在又有一个可以在课堂上讲的故事了
An example of how I am applying the three Ps."
一个应用三个P的例子"
Distraction- very easy.
分心 很简单
I had the best distraction right next to me.
我旁边就有最好的分心工具
Shirell.And then,perspective.
Shirell 然后是转换角度
Is this really going to matter a year from now that
一年之后这会有影响吗
I didn't exercise before a class
我在上课前没有锻炼
and that I didn't go over lecture notes twice
我没有复习两遍备课笔记
but only once before class?
而是只复习了一遍
So I'm not gonna give a class which is 95 percent,
所以我上课就不能发挥95%
but just 90 percent.
只能发挥90%
Is this really going to matter? No.
这真的很重要吗 不重要
But at the same time,I said to myself,
但同时我对自己说
"I still want to be able to enjoy the here and now."
"我仍然希望能享受当下"
So I took my time,spent time with Shirell,
于是我和Shirell呆在一起
stayed with her a few more,
陪她久一点的时间
extra minutes in day care- we played together,
在托儿所陪她久一点 我们一起玩
and then went home,much more relaxed,much calmer,
然后我更放松 更平静地回家了
having applied the three Ps to an actual situation that arose.
将三个P应用于实际发生的情况
Permission to be human- acceptance.
准许自己为人 接受它
Focusing on the positive- benefit finding.
关注积极的一面
And finally,the ability to shift perspective-
最后就是转换角度的能力
when do I want to zoom out and ask this,
我什么时候要退一步问自己
"do I need to sweat over it now?
"我现在需要为此伤神吗
And when do I want to be immersed in the here and now?"
我什么时候想沉浸于当下"
Think about this technique.And again very simple.
想想这个技巧 非常简单
Now this technique is not equivalent to an inoculation,
这个技巧并不等于可以一劳永逸
meaning it's not OK- now you learn the technique;
你现在学到了这个技巧
I know about the three Ps.
我知道三个P
Now for the rest of my life,it's going to help me.
之后我的人生中 它都能帮助我
That's not how it works.
它并不是这样
It works much more like a pill-
它更像是一种药丸
that you need to take on a regular basis,
你要经常定期服用
meaning if you are going through a difficult time,
也就是说每当你经历一次困境
apply the three Ps.
就应用三个P
And the more you apply them,the faster it is.
你应用的越多 生效就越快
Now very often as I mention,the term three Ps.
正如我所说的 三个P
Already automatically I go through that process.
我几乎就是自动过一遍这个过程
Permission.Positive.Perspective.It's much faster now.
许可 积极 转换角度 现在已经快了很多
Because I used it.Because I practiced it.
因为我应用它 不断地练习它
So use it constantly.Try a few times.
所以你要不断地用它 多试几次
Again,bring together a lot of the ideas
我们总结了很多
that we have discussed in the course.OK.
课上讲过的内容
Year and a half ago,
一年半前
I had the privilege of spending a full day
我有幸被Martin Seligman邀请
with Martin Seligman inviting me to his home.
到他家去玩了一整天
And we were sitting down in his beautiful rose garden,
我们坐在他漂亮的玫瑰园中
rose garden that he writes about often.
就是他经常写的那个玫瑰园
And sitting and talking about positive psychology-
坐在那儿聊积极心理学
it's past; it's present; and more than anything,it's future.
它的过去 它的现在 以及更重要的是 它的未来
We talked about education,about what he was doing in his classes
我们讲到了教育 讲到他在他的课上做了什么
as well as what I was doing in my classes.
我在我的课上做了什么
And then,halfway through the conversation,
然后对话进行到一半时
he suddenly stopped and said,
他突然停住说
"Tal,you know what the problem is with psychology today?
"Tal 你知道当今心理学的问题是什么吗
Not just with positive psychology; with psychology today."
不仅仅是积极心理学 而是当今的心理学"
And I said,"what?" Immediately taking out my notebook.
我说"是什么" 然后马上拿出我的笔记本
And he said,"you know,the problem with psychology today
他说"当今心理学的问题在于
is that our focus has mostly been neck up,
我们关注的大多是脖子以上
whereas most of what happens to us is neck down."
而真正发生在我们身上的问题都在脖子以下"
Our focus has been neck up;
我们关注的大多是脖子以上
and most of what happens to us is neck down.
而真正发生在我们身上的问题都在脖子以下
Now hearing this was very important for me.
听到这番话对我很重要
It was double important hearing
尤其是从Martin Seligman
from Martin Seligman for various reasons.
那里听到 就更为重要了
First of all,Martin Seligman has always been ahead of the game.
首先 Martin Seligman总是走在前面的
He has,you know,brought cognitive psychology into...
他引领了认知心理学
when it wasn't,it was hardly known,
在它还未盛行
when behaviorism was dominant.
行为主义还是主流的时候
So his research is ahead of his time.
因此他的研究是超前于时代的
He brought positive psychology,
他开创了积极心理学
or integrated it as a unified field of study.
或者说将其整合为一门学科领域
And Martin Seligman-
Martin Seligman
also the second thing beyond him being a visionary
除了他是一个有远见并且
and very important psychologist-
很重要的心理学家之外
he was also one of the founders of cognitive psychology.
他还是认知心理学的创始人之一
I mean,what is the cognitive therapy about? It's about neck up.
认知疗法是怎样的 就是关于脖子以上的
And for him to say,we have been focusing too much on neck-up
按照他的说法 我们过分关注脖子以上
and we need to go neck down.
我们需要关注脖子以下
That means he thought about it a lot.
这就意味着他已经想了很多
That means he really studied this phenomenon
这意味着他确实研究了这种现象
and really understands that we need a serious shift here.
确实了解了我们需要一个大的转型
And he is very right.
而他十分正确
And this is the topic of the next two lectures.
这将是下两节课的话题
In fact what I'm going to offer you is a "wonder drug".
实际上我要跟你们讲的是一种"灵药"
And this is only for students in 1504.
只提供给上1504课的学生
OK,the auditors as well.
旁听的也算
You can have that "wonder drug" too.
你们也可以得到"灵药"
And here is what the "wonder drug" is going to be doing for you.
"灵药"将给你们带来这样的好处
The "wonder drug" is going to make you feel good.Real good.
"灵药"能使你们感觉很好 非常好
Your self- esteem is going to increase significantly;
你的自尊将显著提升
you are going to be more confident about yourself,
你会更加自信
about who you are,about your place in the world,
更加自信你在社会上的地位
in social settings,on your own-
对自己更加自信
you are just going to have higher levels of self-esteem.And
你会得到更高的自尊
we know that self-esteem is associated with tons of good stuff,
我们都知道自尊跟许许多多好东西相关联
which we'll talk about two weeks from now.
我们两周后会讲到
You are going to feel much calmer,much more centered.
你会觉得更平静 生活更有重心
You are even going to get smarter taking that drug.
有了"灵药" 你甚至能变得更聪明
It's remarkable.
效果是显著的
I mean you are starting to get a little bit worried here.
你们开始有点担心了
It's also going to make you more attractive.
它还会使你更吸引人
You are going to feel more attractive
你会觉得自己更吸引人
and you are going to exude more attractiveness.
你也会散发出更大的魅力
Again this drug has been tested time and again.
这个"灵药"已经被测试了很多遍了
And I'm talking...
我说了
This is all research; this is not just whim.
这都是研究成果 不是异想天开
Here I am selling you something real,
我是在向你们推销真的东西
something that actually works.And
真正有效的东西
I should add that there are no negative side effects to this drug.
我还要说这药没有任何消极的副作用
On the contrary,there are tons of positive side effects
相反 它还有无数积极的作用
that I didn't even mention here.
我数都数不过来
More than that,you can rest assure it's legal.
不仅如此 它还是绝对合法的
I know you were concerned here,but you can take it.
我知道你们有点担心 但你们会接受的
You can take it.You can handle it.
你们能处理好
You don't need to worry about it.
不需要担心
And if anyone comes to you,and is concerned about
如果有人来找你 很担心你怎么
how you suddenly changed as a result of this drug,
用了这个药 突然就变了个人
you can send them to me.
你可以让他们来找我
And finally,I'm not going to charge you for it.
最后 我不会收你们的钱
I should charge you for it.
我本该收钱的
But I'm not a good business man,
但我不是个好商人
so I'm going to give it to you for free over the next two lessons
所以我接下来的两节课会免费发放给你们
And here is the drug.
这就是"灵药"
In fact,it's not just a drug.It's a cocktail.
事实上它不仅仅是种药 是一杯鸡尾酒
It's a cocktail of drugs,
是一杯药做的鸡尾酒
because they seem to work best in many situations.
因为它们似乎要很多东西组合才能发挥最好的作用
So here is the cocktail.
这就是那个鸡尾酒
I hope you are listening now.
我希望你们都在听
Because this is very important.
因为这很重要
The wonder drug: 30 minutes of physical exercise,4 times a week.
灵药就是 半小时的锻炼 每周四次
The second component of the cocktail:
鸡尾酒的第二个成分
at least 15 minutes of mindful exercise 6 or 7 times a week.
至少十五分钟的意念锻炼 每周六到七次
The third component of this cocktail with all these benefits:
鸡尾酒的第三个成分就是
8 hours of sleep more or less per 24 hours.
每24小时睡8个小时
And the final component of the cocktail: 12 hugs a day.
最后一个成分就是 每天12个拥抱
The last one- you can overdose on.
最后一个可以过量
Or rather you can- you can have as much as you like.
你想加多少就加多少
But at least 12 hugs a day.
但至少每天要有12个拥抱
If you take,if you take this drug...
如果你服用这个药
You may hug.That's fine.
你们可以拥抱 没关系
This is 1504! C'mon! But no sleeping in class.
这可是幸福课 但不要在课堂上睡觉
If you take this drug,this cocktail,I guarantee,
如果你服用这个药 这个鸡尾酒 我保证
I guarantee many of the benefits,if not all of the benefits and
我保证以上提到的很多好处 就算不是全部
possibly many more benefits that I've just talked about before.
说不定还会比那更多 都会实现
You see today,only today,
你们可以看到只有今天
we are beginning to understand the connection
我们才开始认识到精神和
between mind and body.
肉体之间的联系
One of the people,the first people to really understand
有一个人 第一个真正认识到的人
who we'll talk about in next two classes is Jon Kabat-Zinn.
我们接下来的两节课会讲到的 就是Jon Kabat-Zinn
In his wonderful book,"Full Catastrophe Living"-
以及他的著作 《全灾难人生》
a phrase taken from Zorba the Greek,
摘自《希腊人佐巴》的一个短语
Jon Kabat-Zinn: "Perhaps the most fundamental development
Jon Kabat-Zinn说"也许行为治疗
in behavioral medicine is the recognition
最基础的进展就是认识到
that we can no longer think about health
我们不能再认为健康
as being solely a characteristic of the body or the mind
仅仅是身体或者精神的一个独立属性
because body and mind are interconnected."
因为精神和肉体是内在联系的"
This is essentially a rejection
这可是否定了
of hundreds of years of Western thinking.
千百年来西方的观念
Cartesian dualism,René Descartes-
笛卡尔的二元论
"the mind and the body are two irreconcilable separate entities."
"意识和物质是两种绝对不同的实体"
And this permeated medicine.
这也渗透到了医学之中
How do we "fix" a person like we fix a machine,we fix the body.
我们"修"一个人就像修机器一样 修他的身体
The mind is something entirely separate from it.
他的精神则是完全没有关系的
And again,Descartes didn't invent it.
笛卡尔也不是凭空创造出的理论
We can see seeds of Cartesian dualism in the works of plato,
我们可以在柏拉图的作品中看到笛卡尔二元论的种子
which then Aristotle tried to negate,
之后亚里士多德试图反对
recreating the mind/body connection,
重新建立精神和肉体之间的联系
but again was made clear very evident
但最终还是二元论成为主流
in the West with Descartes in the 17th century.
由十七世纪笛卡尔倡导
Then comes along Jon Kabat-Zinn; comes along Herbert Benson;
然后就有了Jon Kabat-Zinn 有了Herbert Benson
comes along Ellen Langer; comes along Tara Bennett Goleman.
有了Ellen Langer 有了Tara Bennett Goleman
Psychologists,doctors who understand the connections-
这些心理学家 医生了解这种联系
comes along John Sarno,a medical doctor from NYU,
还有John Sarno 纽约大学的一个医学教授
New York University medical school
纽约大学医学院的
and shows how with our thinking,
他们告诉我们通过我们的想法
we can overcome most of our back problems
我们可以解决大多数背痛的问题
or Carpal Tunnel Syndrome,
或者腕管综合症
showing the connection between mind and body,
显示出精神和肉体之间的联系
or a placebo effect- staggering effects.
或者是安慰剂的作用 非常惊人
Remember we talked about it- reversing the effect of Ipecac
还记得我们说它能起到和催吐剂相反的作用
and asking how can we use that mind and body
以及我们如何用精神和肉体
to help each other to launch a virtuous cycle between the two,
互相形成一个良性循环
while the mind helps body and body helps mind?
精神帮助肉体 肉体帮助精神
I want to begin by talking about physical exercise-
我想从身体锻炼开始讲起
the first component of that cocktail,
鸡尾酒的第一个成分
the first component of the wonder drug.
灵药的第一个成分
What's happening today?
当今社会怎么了
Today there is reduction of physical work.
当今社会普遍缺乏运动
More and more people today
现在越来越多人
have the "luxury" of not having to physically work hard.
享有无需进行辛苦体力劳动的"特权"
And I put it in quotes,because it's one of the manifestations
我用了引号 因为这是特权中的
of the under-privilege of the privilege.
非特权的表现
You see,in the past,we have to run after a deer for lunch,
在过去 我们要去追一只鹿才能有饭吃
or run away from a lion so that we don't become lunch.
或者逃脱一只狮子 这样才不会被吃掉
We had to gather berries for desert.
我们要采摘果子作甜点
What do we do today? Go to the desert table in our house.
我们现在呢 去家里的甜点桌子就行了
Or call out for pizza.
或者叫份比萨
In the past,we had to gather logs if we wanted to keep warm.
在过去 我们要想取暖就得收集木材
Today what do we do? This exercise.
而现在呢 就这样
Turn up the thermometer.And we pay a price.
打开暖气 然后为此付出代价
But you know when I grew up,
我长大之后
when I was growing up in Israel,I remember...
当我在以色列长大时 我记得...
You know Israel is a Mediterranean country,
以色列是个内陆国家
2 - 4 pm is siesta time.Very quiet.
下午两点到四点是午休时间 非常安静
Kids are not out on the street.
孩子们都不到街上去
But at 4:00,sometimes even at 3:59,
但四点整 有时甚至是3:59时
every day there was a shout from the street,
每天都会从街上传来一声叫声
calling "Taaaaal! Soccer!"
叫着"Tal 踢足球"
Then calling other kids,"soccer!" Or "Hide and seek!"
然后叫其他的小孩 "踢足球"或者"捉迷藏"
Or "running around!"
或者"抓人游戏"
That's what we did from 4 pm after siesta time
这是我们在午休时间之后从下午四点
until 9 when we went to sleep and mom called us to have dinner.
一直到晚上九点睡觉 还有妈妈喊吃晚饭时做的事
What happens today in Israel?
而今天在以色列呢
And not just in Israel,around the world,at 4 pm?
不仅仅是以色列 全世界 下午四点是怎样的
It's not going down and playing soccer,and running around.
不是下楼踢足球或跑来跑去
It's continuing to be on the computer.
而是继续坐在电脑前
It's continuing to watch television.
继续看电视
And as a result of that,as a result of the fact,
结果就导致了
we have become so much more sedentary.
我们更习惯于坐着
We are paying a very high price.
我们付出了非常高昂的代价
Of course on the physical level,
当然是从身体上来说
but even more than that,on the psychological level.
但除此之外还有心理上的代价
It is no coincidence that
这不是巧合
the levels of depression have gone up 10 fold.
抑郁的程度已经增加了十倍
It is no coincidence since the 1960s-
这不是巧合 从20世纪60年代算起
it is no coincidence that
这不是巧合
the average age the onset of depression today is just under 15.
当今抑郁症的平均发生年龄刚好只有15岁
Or as in 1960s,the average onset of depression was around 30.
而在20世纪60年代 抑郁症的平均发生年龄是30岁
It is because we have stopped exercising.
这是因为我们停止了锻炼
We have stopped exerting effort and energy.
我们停止发挥力量
It is no coincidence that
这不是巧合
the levels of ADD and ADHD are skyrocketing-
注意力缺陷多动症的病例指数上升
not to mention,and I'll mention later,
更不用说 我之后也会说到
the physical consequences of sedentary life.
宅的生活方式的后果
You see exercise is not a luxury; it's a need.
锻炼不是种奢侈 这是种需要
And it's a need just like oxygen;
就像氧气那样的需要
it's a need just like certain vitamins
就像维生素那样的需要
or a need just like protein and carbohydrates- our needs.
就像蛋白质和碳水化合物那样的需要
We weren't made,
我们不是
we weren't born to sit in front of a computer all day long,
不是生来就要坐在电脑面前一整天的
or just to talk all day long.
也不是一整天聊天的
Yeah we are meant to do it at the end of the day
我们是要在一天结束时
after we have hunted and gathered.
打完猎采完果子之后干这些事的
And whether it's by God,or whether it's by evolution,or both,
不管是上帝决定 还是进化决定 还是两者共同决定的
we now have a need for physical exercise.
我们都有对锻炼的需求
And when we frustrate a need,whether it's a need for vitamins,
如果我们不能满足某种需求 无论是对维生素的需求
whether it's a need for protein or a need for exercise,
对蛋白质的需求 还是对锻炼的需求
we pay a price-
我们都要付出代价
both physical price as well as psychological price.
既包括生理上的代价 也包括心理上的代价
Seneca- over 2000 years ago,the Greek philosopher:
塞内加 两千年前的希腊哲学家说
"Our forefathers lived every jot as well as we,
"我们的祖先和我们过着一样的生活
when they provided and dressed their own meat
他们靠自己的双手
with their own hands; lodged upon the ground,
来获得食物 驻扎在大地上
and were not as yet come to the vanity of gold and gems."
还未受到黄金与宝石的诱惑"
This is Seneca,a very thoughtful philosopher,
这是塞内加 一个很有思想的哲学家说的
talking about the lack of physical exercise
讲到他那个时代存在的
that existed in his time.
缺乏锻炼的现象
How much more is it today? When today we are living in our age,
现在这种现象严重了多少呢 今天在我们这个时代
the way that not even royalty lived just 100 or 200 years ago,
一两百年前连皇家都过不上的生活
the easy life,the luxurious life,
方便的 奢侈的生活
and it's the under-privilege of the privilege.
这是特权中的非特权
We are paying the price for it.
我们要为此付出代价
Let's see what our psychologist has to say about this.
让我们来看看心理学家是怎么说的
Ellen DeGeneres on the state of affairs.
Ellen DeGeneres针砭时事
[VIDEO]Ellen DeGeneres "HERE AND NOW":
"此时此刻"
We're lazy.We have buttons doing everything.
我们很懒 做什么事都一个按钮搞定
There is no physical activity attached to anything anymore.
做什么事都不用体力了
Even the garage door opening-
即使是开车库门
we used to get out of the car and open up the garage door.
我们曾经要下车 打开车库门
Now there is a button you push,you know.
现在就只用按一个按钮
And the car window.
还有车窗
This became too much!
这太过分了
I don't want to turn buttons I just wanna fresh air!
我不想按按钮 我只想呼吸新鲜空气
We still use that gesture
我们现在还在用这个手势
if we want someone to roll their window down in traffic.
如果想让某人把车窗摇下来的话
We still use that.Even now nobody's got it.
我们还在用 虽然已经没人知道是什么意思
Because we'd look like idiots if we did this.
因为如果我们这样做就会像个傻子
We're lazy.We used to have breath mints.
我们很懒 我们以前有薄荷糖
Now we have breath strips.
现在有洗牙糖
They just dissolve all on our tongue for us.
它们帮我们把舌头上的东西都溶掉
How lazy..Can we not suck anymore?
真是懒啊 我们不能吸吮了吗
Aa..put it on...I'm tired! Aaa...I had a hard day!
放上来吧 我累了 我今天好辛苦
Dr.Tal Ben-Shahar:Let me share with you a few studies
我和你们分享几个
about the effect of this kind of life style.
关于这种生活方式的影响的研究
This was done by Michael Babyak
是由Michael Babyak
and his colleagues at Duke Medical School.
以及他在杜克大学医学院的同事共同完成的
This was a very important study that
这是个很重要的研究
launched other numerous studies that
做了很多很多的实验
replicated this and showed how this applies,
模仿这个 并显示出这有多现实
how exercise is important just for depression,
锻炼有多重要 不仅对于抑郁
also for other areas.
还有其他方面
So what Michael Babyak did
Michael Babyak做的实验是
was bringing in 156 patients with major depression.
找了156个抑郁症患者
These are people who have a number of symptoms,
这些人有各种各样的症状
among which are insomnia,eating disorders,listlessness-
包括失眠 饮食不规律 无精打采
lack of desire to act,depressed mood,
不愿动弹 情绪低落
many of them suicidal with attempts or thoughts about suicide
其中很多人都有自杀的想法或倾向
and on and on.
诸如此类
These people who are in bad,very bad shape.
这些人身体都非常不好
And he brought them into the lab
他将他们带到实验室
and randomly divided them into 3 groups.
随机分为三组
The first group was the exercise group;
第一组是锻炼组
second group was put on medication;
第二组服药
and the third group was put on medication and exercise.
第三组既服药又锻炼
The kind of medication was the antidepressant,Zoloft,
他们所服用的药是抗抑郁药 左洛复
the second most popular,common antidepressant after Prozac-
继百忧解之后最普遍的抗抑郁药
very powerful; works.
非常有效
A lot of studies,compared to placebos,showing that Zoloft works
很多研究 以安慰剂为对照 证明左洛复是有效的
An SSRI.
是一种选择性5-羟色胺再摄取抑制剂
The exercise that they were put on
他们所做的运动
was 30 minutes of moderate difficulty-
是半个小时中等难度的
so aerobic physical exercise-
有氧运动
so it could be jogging or race-walking; it could be swimming.
可能是慢跑或者竞走 也可能是游泳
Not too hard,but moderate difficulty of exercise.
不会太难 中等难度的运动
Three times a week for 30 minutes.
一周三次 每次半小时
And then he followed these three groups:
然后跟踪调查这三组人
exercise group,the medication group,
锻炼组 服药组
and the exercise & medication group- followed them for 4 months.
锻炼加服药组 跟踪调查了四个月
And here are the results.
这是得到的结果
What do you want to see? C
你们预期会是什么结果
How many of the 156 patients,or 52 per group,
这156个病人 或者每组52个病人中
how many of them get over their major depression?
有多少治好了抑郁症
And what he found was that in each one of the three groups,
他发现这三组中的每一组
over 60 percent got better by the end of the 4 months.
四个月后都有超过60%的人情况有所好转
They were not experiencing
他们不再出现
the symptoms of major depression anymore,
抑郁症的症状
or most of the symptoms at the very least.
或者大部分症状
They were no longer,could no longer be categorized by the DSM-IV
他们不能再按照美国精神病诊断标准
as having major depression.
被诊断为抑郁症
There was no significant difference among the groups
在各组之间没有显著的区别
except for one difference: the group that exercised only-
只有一个区别 那个只锻炼的组
it took them a little bit longer
需要更长一点的时间
to get over their major depression.
来治好抑郁症
So with the medication,it usually took probably around,
在服药的情况下 一般要花上
between 1 or 2 weeks,around 10 days to overcome their depression
约一到两个星期 差不多十天来治好
for the 60 percent who were helped.
60%受试者的抑郁症
For the exercise only group,it took closer to a month.
对于仅仅锻炼的组 他们花了差不多一个月
But after the first month,once they got better,
但在第一个月后 一旦他们好一些之后
there was no difference.
就没有什么区别了
All three groups benefited as much.
三个组都出现了好转
Now very important point:
注意很重要的一点
this does not mean that we should do away with antidepressants
这并不代表我们就要废除抗抑郁药
or anti-anxiety pills or Ritalin for ADD/ADHD.
或者抗焦躁的药物 或者治疗多动症的利他林
Not at all.
完全不是
What it is saying though that
他要说的是
we need to perhaps first ask whether exercise is,
我们首先要问的是锻炼
or lack there of is the underlying reason for the experience.
或者缺乏锻炼是不是其潜在原因
Now why should not we do away
我们为什么不废除药物呢
if the results are very similar between exercise and medication?
如果锻炼和服药的效果如此类似的话
Why shouldn't we do away with medication? Here is why.
我们为什么不废除服药呢 原因在于
You see,let's say...Let me just draw this circle.
比如说 让我画一个圆
No.Let's say
假设
this is the total population of people who are depressed.
这是所有抑郁的人的集合
We know that Zoloft,
我们知道左洛复
or antidepressant medication helps about 60 percent of them.
或者说抗抑郁症帮了他们60%的人
And we know that exercise also helps 60 percent.
我们知道锻炼同样帮了60%的人
However,it is not the same 60 percent.
但不是同一个60%
There is overlap by definition,
在定义上有重叠
because it is more than 50 percent.
因为多于50%
But it doesn't help the same people.
它们帮助的不是同一群人
So there are people who are only helped by medication;
有的人仅仅受了服药的好处
there are people who are only helped by exercise;
有的人仅仅受了锻炼的好处
and there are people who are helped by both.
还有的人两者好处皆有
So it's not saying let's do away with medication.
所以不能说 废除服药吧
It is important.It helps.
它很重要 它确实有用
However it also says "let's try exercise,
但结果同时显示 "试试锻炼吧
because I may be helped by exercise and not medication,
因为我有可能是得益于锻炼而不是服药
or I may be helped by both.
或者得益于两者
Here is the clincher though in the study:
研究的关键在于
so what we are looking for,as I look in all these studies,
我们在看这些研究时 想搞清楚的是
is the relapse rates,meaning 6 months after the end of the study
复发率 实验结束半年后
when we no longer give medication,
我们不再让他们服药
when we no longer push the participants to exercise
不再强迫被试者锻炼
three times a week at least,what happens after 6 months?
每周至少三次 半年后如何了呢
And here is what they found:
这是他们发现的结果
the relapse rate of the group on medication only-
仅仅服药组的复发率只有
38 percent out of the 60+ percent who got better returned back
60%多好转的人中有38%人回头
and had the major depression again,38 percent,over a third;
又有了抑郁症的症状 38% 超过了1/3
the group that did medication
这个既服药又锻炼的组
and exercise- relapse rate of 31 percent,
复发率为31%
just under a third of the 60+ percent who got better;
刚好比三分之一少一点 在这些60%好转的人中
relapse rates of the exercise group only-
仅仅锻炼的组的复发率
and remember they could continue exercise or not;
他们可以选择继续锻炼也可以不锻炼
that was entirely up to them-
完全看他们自己
the relapse rate of the exercise only group,9 percent.
仅仅锻炼的组的复发率 为9%
Remarkable results.
十分令人惊讶的结果
Similar results earlier than the year 2000,
和2000年之前的实验结果非常相似
all the way back in 1984 for dysthymia.
追溯到1984年的精神抑郁症
Dysthymia is usually longer lasting,
精神抑郁症通常持续时间较长
but less acute form of depression.
但没一般抑郁症那么急性
So it's a deep feeling of sadness.
是一种深层的悲伤的情绪
Lasts for much longer than major depression.
比抑郁症持续时间长很多
But also exercise helps this.
但锻炼对它也有帮助
Now when I first saw this study again there are dozens,
在我第一次看到这个研究时
there are hundreds of studies by now,
现在已经有无数这样的研究了
replicating this phenomenon on different,
在不同的领域重复这样的现象
different areas- as I'll talk about in a minute,
我等下会讲到
I said,"wow! This is amazing!"
我说 "哇 太不可思议了"
So exercise is like taking antidepressant- seems like it.
不锻炼就像服用抗忧郁药 效果很像
Exercise is like taking antidepressant.
锻炼就像服用抗忧郁药物
But when I thought about further,
但我再仔细想想
I realized that wasn't the case.
就发现并不是这样
It's not that exercising is like taking an antidepressant,
不是锻炼就像服用抗忧郁药
it's rather that not exercising is like taking a depressant.
而是不锻炼就像服用抗忧郁药
This is more than just a semantic difference.
这不仅仅是语言上的区别
Why? Because you see,we weren't made to be sedentary.
为什么 因为我们不是生来为了坐着的
We weren't made to sit in front of the computer
我们不适合长时间坐在电脑前
or in the classroom.
或者教室里
We were made to run after that deer or run away from that lion.
我们本来应该去逐鹿 或者逃离狮子的追捕
And we frustrate a need,as we've talked about earlier,
而当我们无法满足这种需求时 正如之前讲的
we frustrate a need,we pay a price.
我们无法满足需求 就要付出代价
So let's say our God-given or genes-given level of happiness,
比方说上帝或者基因决定的幸福程度
our base level of happiness is here.
基本的幸福程度有这么高
Our set point or set range is here.
我们固有的水平就这么高
When we don't exercise,
如果我们不锻炼
what we are doing is that we are lowering that base level to here
我们就把这个基本水平降到这里
If our normal level is here,
如果我们的正常水平在这里
what we are doing when we don't exercise,
当我们不锻炼时
we are lowering it to here.
就会把它降到这里
And then whereas we could have lived our life up here
然而我们是可以达到这样的幸福程度的
with all the vicissitudes,and hopefully upward spiral,
即使有兴衰变迁 也可能是螺旋式上升的
what we are doing is we are living our lives
而我们现在是经历了
the same ups and downs- only a much lower level here.
同样的起伏 只不过是在更低的水平上
And we struggle just to get to our God-given
我们努力挣扎着到达上帝决定
or genes-given level of happiness.
或基因决定的幸福程度
You know I'm not a clinical psychologist.I'm not a therapist.
我不是个临床心理学家 我不是心理治疗师
However,
但是
if I were one,a prerequisite for me for treating people,
如果我是的话 我治疗病人的一个前提
for working with people would have been physical exercise,
就是体育锻炼
or at the very least,
或者至少
being my No.1 priority of helping them to physically exercise.
我对他们第一个要求就是要进行身体锻炼
Cause very often they would come
因为他们通常都是
because they don't have the motivation perhaps to exercise.
没有体育锻炼的动力
But that would be my No.1 priority,
但那会是我的首要要求
either to make it a prerequisite for being treated
要么是治疗的前提条件
or to make it a top priority.
要么就是首要的要求
Why? Because I don't want to fight nature.
为什么 因为我不想和自然作对
I don't want to fight nature
我不想和自然作对
so that the person I'm working with gets to their God-given
所以我要治疗的那个人必须达到上帝或者
or genes-given level of well being.
基因决定的幸福程度
I want to work with nature.
我想和自然合作
Nature to be commanded must be obeyed.
自然所要求的必须遵守
One of the dictates of nature
自然的命令之一
is that we need to be physically active.
就是我们要活跃地运动
Now I was just talking about this over dinner-
我在晚餐时就讲了这个
I had dinner with Dave Fish,the tennis coach and his wife,
我和网球教练Dave Fish 以及他妻子
Bonnie Mosland,who is a clinical therapist.
Bonnie Mosland 一个临床心理学家共进晚餐
And she told me,"yeah."
然后她跟我说 "对"
You know she's been treating people for years.
她已经治疗了很多年病人了
"That's what I do.
"我就是这样的
Prerequisite for treatment with me is physical exercise."
我治疗的前提条件就是你必须进行身体锻炼"
So there are apprently psychologists
确实有心理学家
who understand the importance of exercise.
能够理解锻炼的重要性
Why fight nature here?
为什么要和自然作对呢
When you can start and the base level can be here?
当你可以在这个水平开始的时候
Some other benefits- again all based on research.
还有其他好处 都是基于这个研究的
You've read some of it in your readings,
你们在阅读中可能读过一些
but more benefits to exercise.
锻炼还有很多其他好处
First psychological benefit: self-esteem.
首先是心理上的好处 自尊
On a few levels- first of all,bodily self-esteem,
从很多层面上说 首先是身体上的自尊
we feel better about ourselves;
我们自我感觉更良好
and also general self-esteem,we feel better about ourselves.
也包括整体的自尊 我们感觉更良好
State as well as trait self-esteem increases.
不管是整体还是特征性的自尊都得到提升
In other words,as we feel right after we exercise
换句话说 不但锻炼之后我们马上就能感觉到
but also as we feel in the long term
而且长时间内我们都能感觉到
if we have a regular exercise regime.
如果我们保持规律的锻炼计划
So both state as well as trait self-esteem is increased.
所以整体和特征性的自尊都会得到提升
Anxiety and stress-
焦虑和压力
one of the things that is most susceptible to exercise.
是最容易被锻炼所影响的事之一
You know Tammy can tell,
Tammy能够看出来
my wife can tell if I have exercise for more than 48 hours.
我妻子能够看出来我48小时内有没有锻炼
You know when I come home,
我回到家时
she would say,"when did you last exercise?"
她会说"你最近一次锻炼是什么时候"
Why? Because she feels.
为什么 因为她有感觉
she has the sense of you know,
她能察觉到
a little bit rough around the edges,a little bit more tense.
是不是有点小小的变化 或者稍微有点压力
Again,as I mentioned in previous classes,
正如我在之前的课上讲过的
I have inclination for anxiety.
我有焦虑的倾向
Exercise is my drug.It's my wonder drug.
锻炼就是我的药 我的灵药
At the very least,every other day.At the very least.
至少要保证每隔一天锻炼一次 每隔一天
It's been used very successfully for numerous clinical disorders.
这对无数临床的病症都非常有效
Even schizophrenia.
包括精神分裂症
In conjunction with,not itself,
它并不是自己起作用
in conjunction with therapy and various drugs.
而是和治疗以及药物协同起作用
But it enhances the likelihood of a success
但它增加了成功的可能性
if you exercise as well.
如果你去锻炼的话
Also ADD and ADHD- not always enough,but very often enough.
还有注意力缺陷多动症 不一定足以治愈 但通常十分有效
People who exercise and exercise regularly-
那些坚持常规锻炼的人
much more likely to get over ADD and ADHD.
更容易克服注意力缺陷多动症
Why? Because there are numerous effects on our brain,
为什么呢 因为这对我们的大脑有无数的影响
numerous effects on our brain.
对大脑有无数的影响
For example,the exact same chemicals that are released
比方说我们释放的那个化学物质
when we form new neural pathways-
当我们形成新的神经通路时
remember neurogenesis or neuroplasticity-
还记得神经形成或者神经可塑性吗
the exact chemicals that
正是这个形成新的
we need to form new neural pathways are created when we exercise.
神经通路时会释放的化学物质 就能在我们锻炼时产生
In other words,after we go for a run.
换句话说 我们去跑个步之后
This is the time when our brain is most susceptible
这时我们的大脑就最适合于
to creating new neural pathways.
形成新的神经通路
So if you exercise in the morning,during the day,
所以如果你在早上去锻炼 那么一整天
you retain much better the material you have read
你就能更好地吸收你阅读的东西
or you have heard.
或者你听到的东西
You are much more creative after exercise,
锻炼之后你会更有创造力
I mean if you have exercise for a few days.
如果你已经锻炼了一段时间的话
And also it helps us release these chemicals
同时它能帮助我们释放
in the exact right amount- no more,no less than we need.
恰好够量的这种化学物质 不多也不少
Why? Because this is nature.Knows best what we need.
为什么 因为这是自然 自然比我们更懂我们需要什么
And we release these exact right amount of chemicals
我们释放这刚好足量的化学物质
that we are at our best.
就达到了我们的最好状态
This is by the way why again as I mentioned earlier religiously
这又是一种方式 我之前提到过的
I run before every lecture.Well,I don't always run.
我每堂课之前都去跑步 不是次次都能去跑
I like running outside but it's not always possible.
我喜欢在外面跑 但不是每次都可以
So I jump on my trampoline at home.
所以我有时会跳家里的蹦床
I have you know one of the small ones.
我有一个小的
And I jump on them.And I have my pulse meter on me.
我在上面跳 戴着脉冲计
Shouldn't have told you this? No.OK.
不应该告诉你们这个吗 好吧
And I can feel when I haven't,
我能感觉到如果我不这样做
when I don't exercise before lecture.
在上课之前不做锻炼
You know,for example,when I travel,
比如说我去旅行
I arrive right before lecture and don't have time to work out,
刚好赶在上课前回来 没时间去锻炼
I can feel when I read,
我能感觉到我阅读时
my retention rates,my concentration levels,
我的记忆保留率 集中程度
cause as I said earlier,I have mild case of ADHD.
我之前说过 我有轻微的注意力缺陷多动症
And again,exercise is my drug.
锻炼是我的药
Physical benefits.
身体上的好处
Again I am not saying anything new to you here.
我现在跟你们讲的不是什么新内容
But here is a way to think about it.
但你要这样来想它
We all have a genes/God-given level of weight,
我们都有一个基因决定的体重水平
of the right weight for us.
适合我们的体重水平
Now when we exercise,we are there.
当我们锻炼时 我们在那儿
And that is healthy.That is where we should be.
这样就是健康的 是我们应该达到的
When we don't exercise we are going above this weight.
当我们不锻炼时 体重就会超过这个
Just like we go below our base level of well being.
就像降低幸福水平一样
In other words,what exercise does
换句话说 锻炼的作用
is simply bring us back to where we are supposed to be all along,
就是将我们带回我们本来应有的水平
which explains why most diets fail
这也就解释了为什么大多数节食
if not associate with physical exercise as well.
如果不和锻炼一起进行 就很容易失败的原因
Because our bodies will always fight to go back to the base level
因为我们的身体会拼命想要回到原来的水平
to where we are supposed to be.
我们本该有的水平
And if we don't exercise,we will struggle even harder.
如果我们不锻炼 就会挣扎得更辛苦
Chronical disease,whether it's diabetes,
慢性疾病 不管是糖尿病
whether it's heart disease,whether it's cancer.
还是心脏病 抑或是癌症
Once again numbers are staggering,absolutely staggering.
数量是非常惊人的
Diabetes,certain types of diabetes were only experienced
糖尿病 有些糖尿病原本只有45岁以上的人
by people 45 years and older.
才会获得
Today kids in elementary school are getting this kind of diabetes
现在小学生都会得这种糖尿病
and the association is mostly
其原因很大程度上就是
because of nutrition and lack of exercise.
因为营养问题以及缺乏锻炼
People who exercise
经常锻炼的人
are much less prone to these chronical diseases.
更不容易得慢性疾病
Reducing significantly the likelihood of diabetes;
患糖尿病的可能性大大降低
reducing by 50 percent or more the likelihood of heart failure
减少了50%以上患心脏病的风险
and the likelihood of certain kinds of cancer.
以及得癌症的可能性
By over 50 percent reducing their likelihood-
可以降低50%的可能性
again,a wonder drug.
它是灵药
People who exercise regularly have a stronger immune system.
经常锻炼的人免疫系统更强
Well I have to prep you for this.
我要给你们打好提前量
And finally if you haven't been convinced until now,
最后 如果你现在还没被说服
hopefully this will convince you.
希望这个能说服你
(Better Sex) Both men and women.
(更好的性行为) 不管男人还是女人
Strengthens libido- their sexual desire;
都能增强性欲 对性的渴望
enhances the likelihood of orgasms.
能够增加高潮的可能性
People who exercise more regularly have more and better sex.
经常锻炼的人性生活会更美好
Again,a lot of research showing this.
很多研究都证实了这一点
And by the way,this applies to all ages.
它适用于任何年龄
To all ages.Well,not all ages.I hope.21 and on.
不是任何年龄 21岁以上
Now the important thing to remember about exercise-
但是关于锻炼要记住的很重要的一点是
it is not a panacea.
它不是万灵药
It's not a fix-all.
它不是万能的
Remember not everyone benefits from exercise.
记住不是所有人都能从锻炼中获得好处
There are some people for whom medication
对于有的人来说 服药就是
is absolutely the right thing and it's important.
很适合和很重要的方式
However,in many situations,and it's eveident by,by literature,
然而在很多情况下 研究和调查都证实了
by research- in most situations,exercise can help.
在大多数情况下 锻炼是有帮助的
Even it's not on its own.
就算不是它本身的作用
Even in conjunction with something else.It helps.
即使是和别的东西协同作用的 它还是有帮助
And again why fight nature? Why fight it?
为什么要和自然对抗呢
Nature to be commanded must be obeyed.
自然所要求的必须遵守
What's very important is recovery.
还有很重要的一点在于恢复
Let me read you something that
我给你们读读
Dienstbier and Zillig write about in the Handbook
Dienstbier和Zillig在《积极心理学手册》中
of Positive Psychology to researchers in the field: "
对研究者们这样写道
Repeated workouts that are too intense to allow complete recovery
"重复的过于密集的训练 以至于没法及时恢复
may cause endurance athletes to experience 'staleness,'
可能会导致运动员感觉到'泄气'
a syndrome that is characterized
典型的症状为
by increased psychological symptoms of anxiety
更高的焦虑水平
with increased sympathetic nervous system,
更高的神经紧张度
catecholamine,and cortisol base levels."
更高的儿茶酚胺和皮质激素水平"
Now what they are saying here
他们想说的是
is that there can be too much of a good thing.
有时事情是过犹不及的
And this is especially important for perfectionists to understand
尤其是完美主义者要明白这一点
It doesn't mean that more is always better
越多不一定代表越好
when it comes to exercise.
说到锻炼的话
There is too much- and some of the symptoms of overtraining
确实会过度锻炼 有些过度训练的症状
are very similar to the symptoms of undertraining.
会和训练不足的症状十分相似
Higher levels of anxiety,higher levels of staleness,
高水平的焦虑 高水平的泄气
lack of motivation,
失去动力
as well as ultimately could lead to depression.
最终也可能导致抑郁
This is a symptom of a perfectionism.
这是完美主义的一种症状
This is something that I experience when I was an athlete-
我在做运动员时就经历过这样的事
overtraining,not recovering enough,and paying the price.
过度训练 恢复不足 并为此付出了代价
Physically of course with injuries,but also psychologically.
身体上自然是受了伤 而且心理上也受了伤
What I recommend is between 1 to 4 days of rest a week.
我推荐每周有一到四天的休息时间
Ideally you want to exercise 5 or 6 times a week;
理想情况下你想每周锻炼五到六次
at minimum I would say every other day.
我认为至少要保证每两天一次
So it could be 3 or 4 days a week.
这样每周就是三到四天
At minimum every other day.
至少每两天一次
Ideally you may want a little bit more than that.
理想状态下你们可能想更多一点
Each time,about 30 minutes; could go all the way up to an hour.
每次半小时 也可以增加到一小时
The key here is to listen to your body.
关键是要听从你身体的需要
If your body is hurting
如果你的身体很痛苦
beyond the slight discomfort of exercise which is natural,stop.
超出了正常的不舒适范围 赶快停止
If your muscle hurts,stop.
如果肌肉开始酸痛 停下来
Or on the side of too little rather than too much.
宁可少也不要过度
Also one of the ways to listen to your body
还有一种聆听你身体的方法
if you are not as sensitive to it,
如果你没那么敏感的话
is putting on a heart rate monitor,
就是戴个心率监控器
which is something not very expensive,very useful,very helpful.
不是很贵 但非常非常有用
So I know my exercise
这样我就知道我的锻炼
would be around 70 percent of maximum heart rate.
会保持在最高心率的70%左右
70 percent of maximum heart rate for me is about 128.
我最高心率的70%大概是128
So exercise around between 120 and 135.
于是我就在120到135之间锻炼
And then once in a while I also introduce interval training,
偶尔我又会加强一点
while I go all the way up to 90 percent,
达到90%
which is about 165 heart rate for me.
我的差不多是165
But very easy to find out about you know what your heart rate is-
很容易发现你们的心跳
usually maximum heart rate is around 220 minus your age.
通常在最大心率是220减去你的年龄
So if you are 20 your maximum is to 200.
所以如果你20岁 最大心率就是200
Mine,being 37,is 183.
我37岁 所以就是183
Again,more or less.
差不多吧
And then you want to be around 70 percent of it.
然后你就保持在70%的水平
65 percent to 75 percent of it
65%到75%的水平
for moderate effective benefit of exercise.
来获得锻炼的最温和的效果
And to keep in mind that the quantity does affect quality.
记住数量确实会影响质量
And once again we have the graph that
我们再次画个图表
we see so often: the curve linear relationship.
我们经常看到的线性曲线图
So if on this side of the graph,
在图的这边
we had psychological plus physiological benefit,
是心理和生理的好处
and here we have effort or amount of work,
这里是运动量
the graph looks like this,where too little effort is not good.
那么图画出来就是这样 太少了不好
We are compromising on our base level of happiness.
我们要达到基本的幸福水平才行
Too much effort is also not good.
太多了也不好
That's when we experience the staleness and the anxiety.And
这时我们就会感到泄气和焦虑
what we want to get to is more or less around our optimum level.
我们想要达到的是差不多到最适水平
And also optimum level given how much time we have.
而这个最适水平也在于我们能投入多少时间
Yeah,in an ideal world,
在理想情况下
I would work out six times a week for one hour each time.
我每周锻炼六次  每次一个小时
In an ideal world.But I want to do many other things.
在理想情况下是这样 但我还想做很多别的事
So I exercise at least 4 times a week,30 minutes each time.
所以我每周至少锻炼四次 每次半小时
It's good enough for me.Identify what's good enough for you.
这对我来说就足够了 要搞清楚什么对你是足够的
Recovery is important.
恢复也很重要
We talked about recovery on the psychological level.
我们从心理学层面上讲过恢复
Recovery is very important.
恢复很重要
Let me share with you just a quick story about Derek Clayton.
我简要地和你们分享一下Derek Clayton的故事吧
Derek Clayton was a runner in the early 60s,
Derek Clayton是60年代早期的一个长跑运动员
one of the best long distance runners in the world.
世界上最好的长跑运动员之一
One of the best- not the best.
最好的之一 并不是最好的
He ran marathons.
他是跑马拉松的
And the reason why he wasn't the best,many people said,well,
很多人说 他之所以不是最好的
because physically he wasn't that fit or suitable for marathons.
是因为从身体上讲 他不太适合跑马拉松
He was 6 ft 2 in,tall- 1 meter 88.
他身高六尺二 1米88
His veil too max,his maximum heart...
并且他的最大心率
maximum oxygen capacity was not that high,
最大血液溶氧量不是很高
as high as the top runners in the world.
没有其他世界级选手那么高
But what he had going for him was that
但他的优势在于
he was the hardest worker on the circuit.
他是最勤奋的一个
He would run in excess of 100 miles a week.
他每周跑一百多英里
Way over 100 miles a week.Worked very hard.
远远多于一百多英里 非常努力
Sorry.I wrote it down.
抱歉 我写下来了的
Yeah,over 100 miles each week.
对 每周一百多英里
And he became one of the best runners in the world,
于是他成为了世界最好的长跑运动员之一
but never got to be at the very best.
但从来没成为过真正的第一
And then what happened? Because of his hard work,over-exertion,
然后发生什么了呢 由于他的过度刻苦勤奋
he got injured quite seriously
他受了很严重的伤
and couldn't run for a whole month,
一整个月不能跑步
as he was training for one of the most important marathons in-
他当时正在准备非常重要的一项马拉松赛事
this marathon was in Japan.
这个马拉松在日本举行
So for a whole month,couldn't train.
一整个月他都不能训练
Hardly walked.
走路都走不了
About a week before,he started just very lightly jogging.
在比赛一周之前 他开始可以慢慢地跑
And he said he'll run in Japan.
他说他会去日本跑的
He was invited there.He was one of the best runners in the world.
他被邀请去参加了 他是世界最好的长跑运动员之一
He said he'll use it as a training run,
他说他会将其作为一次训练
as part of his training regime for the next marathon.
作为下一次马拉松比赛训练的一部分
So he comes to this marathon,
于是他去参加了这个马拉松
having not trained for over a month,
一个月没有训练
breaks his best personal records by 8 minutes
结果提前八分钟打破他的个人记录
and becomes the first person in history to run a marathon
成为历史上第一个仅用了
in under 2 hours and 10 minutes.
两小时十分钟跑完马拉松的人
Running it in 2 hours 9 minutes and 36 seconds.
两小时9分36秒
1967.
1967年
Continues to train hard.2 years later,over-trains again.
他继续努力训练 两年之后再次训练过度
Gets injured again.
又再次受伤
And once again,for over a month he can't run at all
又一次他没法跑步
and then enters the Belgium marathon.
然后他去参加了比利时马拉松比赛
Breaks his own personal best,breaks the world record:
又打破了他的个人记录 也打破了世界记录
2 hours 8 minute and 33 seconds,
两小时8分33秒
a world record,world best that holds for 12 years.
世界纪录 保持了12年的世界纪录
This is when trainers and athletes began to understand
这时教练和运动员就开始明白
the importance of tapering,the importance of taking time off,
适可而止的重要性 适当休息的重要性
the importance of recovery.
恢复的重要性
There can be too much of a good thing.
有时过犹不及
Very similar story.Joan Benoit.
很相似的故事 Joan Benoit
Ended up winning the 1984 Los Angeles Marathon
最终赢得了1984年洛杉矶马拉松
after having been injured and having,was forced to take time off
在受伤了 被迫休息之后
The Danish Soccer team.
还有丹麦足球队
Another example.I think that's 1991.
另一个例子 我想应该是1991年
Ended up winning the European Championship
最终赢得了欧冠
after being out of the competition,
之前都没在比赛中
being brought in the last minute
在最后一刻才加入
because Yugoslavia was just breaking apart at the time.
因为当时南斯拉夫正搞分裂
So they came in as a replacement for Yugoslavia,
于是他们作为了南斯拉夫的替补
literally taking the Danish team
在预选赛淘汰了之后
after it was eliminated from prelims,
把丹麦队又找过来
bringing them from the beach to play the tournament.
把他们从沙滩上带来打冠军赛
But they had recovered,they were refresh,they were ready to go.
因为他们恢复了 振作了 于是他们准备好了
Recovery is important in sports.
恢复在运动中很重要
It's important on the psychological level.
在心理层面同样很重要
OK.So exercise is good.It's the wonder drug.
锻炼是很好的 是一种灵药
The first part of the cocktail,
鸡尾酒的第一个成分
I would argue,well,one of the most important ones.
我觉得算是最重要的成分
And yet,most people,not at Harvard necessary,
然而很多人 不仅仅在哈佛
but most people around the world don't exercise.
世界上很多人都不锻炼
What are some of the barriers that we need to overcome
为了将定期锻炼引入我们的生活
in order to introduce exercise regularly into our lives?
我们要跨越怎样的障碍
First,it is painful.
首先 这是痛苦的
It's not comfortable to exercise
锻炼不是件舒服的事
at say 70 percent of our maximum heart rate.
比如说到达70%最大心率的锻炼
Doesn't hurt that much,but it's more comfortable to sit
并不会很痛 但显然没有坐在电视机前
in front of the television or play Nintendo.
或者玩任天堂舒服
So what do we do?
那我们该怎么办
The first thing that we can do is divide and conquer.
我们要做的第一件事就是把目标分割 各个攻破
One of the things that especially perfectionists do is that
尤其是完美主义者会做的一件事就是
"OK,so I'm going to start exercising.
"我要开始锻炼了
And to be fit,I need to do 6 miles a day.
为了保持健康 我每天要跑六英里
And that's what I'm going to start running.6 miles a day."
所以我一开始就要每天跑六英里"
And of course what happens very quickly?
很快会怎样呢
The next day you get up and you are hurt.
第二天你起床就会全身酸痛
But you are a perfectionist.
但你是个完美主义者
You are tough.No pain,no gain.
你很坚强 一分耕耘一分收获
And you go out for a run again.
于是你又出去跑步
And what happens? You hurt even more the next day.
然后会怎样呢 你第二天更疼
But you push through the pain.
但你咬牙忍着疼痛
After a few weeks,you get injured.
几个星期之后你就会受伤
But even if you don't get injured,the schema that is created
但即使你不受伤 在你脑海中
in your mind about exercise is the following.
关于锻炼的概念是这样的
It is "exercise equals pain".
"锻炼就等于痛苦"
Now our mind does not like pain.And it tries to avoid pain.
我们的意识是拒绝痛苦的 它总是极力避免痛苦
So let's say you go on a holiday.You stop your exercise regime.
比如说你去度了个假 中断了你的锻炼计划
You stop your exercise regime for a week or two weeks.
中断了一个星期或者两个星期
And you come back.
然后你回来了
It becomes exceedingly difficult to go back exercising.
想重新开始锻炼就变得更难
Why? Because you mind,subconscious mind says,
为什么 因为你的思想 你的潜意识会说
"I don't want to experience this again."
"我不想再经受这个了"
And it prevents you.It paralyzes you.
这会阻止你锻炼 使你瘫痪
This is very often the procrastination that comes through.
这通常就是拖延症发生的时候
Because we don't want to experience that pain.
因为我们不想经历这种痛苦
A much healthier approach is to say "OK.
一种更健康的方式是
So I'll start with walking for a mile.
"我先从走路开始
For 10 minutes,20 minutes walk.
走十分钟 二十分钟的路
Do it for a week or two weeks.And then build it up gradually.
坚持一到两个星期 然后逐渐增加
And again,earn the side of doing too little rather than too much
宁可少也不要过度
Because then exercise,
因为那样锻炼
if I build it up gradually,is not about pain.
如果我逐渐增加 就不是种痛苦
Overtime it even becomes sort of addictive
它逐渐会成瘾
in a positive sense of word,
从积极的角度来看
that we want to do it,that we long for it.
我们想去做它 我们渴望它
So doing it gradually.Also use distracters.
所以要慢慢来 同时要应用让你分心的事物
When I jump on my trampoline-
当我在蹦床上跳时
when I run outside,I have no problem-
在外面跑是不会有问题的
but when I jump on my trampoline,I have to add distracters.
但在蹦床上跳时 我就要用一些分心的事物
It is so boring for me.
我觉得蹦床太无聊了
Again,some people can be on the bike for an hour.
有的人可能会去骑一小时自行车
And they are fine.
那样也没问题
For me it's meditation and that's great.
我更喜欢冥想 这很好
But many people need distracters,whether it's music,
但很多人需要让他分心的事物 不管是音乐
whether it's TV,whether it's my kids running around,
还是电视 还是小孩子在周围跑来跑去
but having something that keeps us going.
但总要找些分散你注意力的事
Social support.
社会支持
The No.1 predictor of exercise success for the long term
长期锻炼成功的最好预测方法就是
is do I do it with other people;
我是否是和其他人一起做的
do I have the social support to do it.
有没有给我社会支持
And once again,this is not right for everyone.
再次强调这不是对每个人都有用的
There are certain people for whom the right thing
对有些人来说更好的方式是
is to do it by themselves.
他们自己去做
This is the time,
有可能的情况是
especially introverts will enjoy just being on their own.
尤其是内向的人 更喜欢自己去做
Just closing their eyes,listening to their music,
闭上眼睛 听着音乐
or listening to their heart rate,whatever it...
或者听着心跳
You know heart beating.
心跳的声音
But they want time by themselves.And that's fine.
他们会想要独自一个人的时间 这是没问题的
But for most people social support helps.Here is the study.
但对大多数人来说 社会支持是有益的 还有个研究
This is done by Wing and Jerry,two psychologists.
由Wing和Jerry 两名心理学家完成的
What they did was introduce individuals to a 4 month program
他们所做的是让人参与一个为期四月的项目
that included behavioral change,that included diet change
包括行为改变 包括饮食改变
and that included exercise change for 4 months.
包括锻炼上的改变 为期四月
The two conditions were either with social support-
分为两种情况 一种是有社会的支持
doing it with your friend and a family member,
和你的朋友或者家人一起做
or without social support.
或者没有社会支持
Those without social support,who did it by themselves,
那些没有社会支持 自己完成的人
76 percent completed the 4 month program
有76%的人完成了这个为期四月的项目
and 24 percent were still doing it 6 months later.
有24%的人还保持到了六个月
So 76 percent did it during the 4 months;
76%保持了四个月
24 percent only,less than a quarter,did it 6 months later.
只有24% 不到四分之一的人 保持到了六个月
Kept up with the behavioral,exercise as well as diet change.
能够保持行为上的 锻炼上的 以及饮食上的改变
The group that had social support,
有他人支持的一组
95 percent completed the 4 months.
95%完成了四个月的项目
95 as opposed to the 76 percent.
95%而不是76%
And 67 percent continued with the regime
同时67%的人维持了这个计划
once the study was over for 6 months later.
保持到了六个月以后
So it enhanced the likelihood of success a great deal.
也就是成功的可能性大大地增加了
Let me show you one last example of social support.
再给你们看一个社会支持的例子
[VIDEO]
录像
OK.So this is not exactly what I mean.
这不是我想说的意思
But social support helps.
但社会支持确实是有帮助的
So start if you haven't started,start today.
所以如果你还没开始 那就从今天开始吧
I'll see you on Thursday.
周四见
[Applause]
[掌声]